Sushil Kumar Dwivedi (MT19AIE323): Good afternoon sir
Ranjan Kumar (MT19AIE295): independent small unit of service
Sushil Kumar Surana (MT19AIE324): section of small services
Ridhima Kohli (B19CSE071): various functions are distributed in different parts as microservices
Abhijit S Iyer (M21CS001): Only the essential services are put together in a module
Jimmi Sinha (MT19AIE247): Single responsibility principle
Apoorv Pal (B19CSE102): in microservices, individual independent services could exist even on separate servers and services interact with each other via a well-defined interface
Abhilash Sharma (MT19AIE202): It is a complete functionality/feature in itself and has its own database
Surbhi Dua (B19CSE088): independent services
Shubham Singh (M21CS016): for ex. multiple browsers used in mobile phone
Shivam Kumar (B19CSE118): do they have to be independent?
Saptashrungi Birajdar (B19CSE076): a service is broader while microservice has small tasks
Sai Vamsi Puttu (MT19AIE303): if its serves part of the functionality but not the entire service
Sushil Kumar Surana (MT19AIE324): may be when it provides output which is not complete and has to be consumed by some other microservice
Abhilash Sharma (MT19AIE202): Sir, by complete I mean single responsibility
Abhijit S Iyer (M21CS001): Taking user input (webpage)
Verification of credentials
Saptashrungi Birajdar (B19CSE076): checking if the email is valid - can be a microservice
Shivam Kumar (B19CSE118): take input, match passwords
Jagadeesh P N (MT19AIE246): auth service, Identity provider service
Amit Kumar Sharma (M20AIE213): Authentications
Ridhima Kohli (B19CSE071): authentication and open dashboard after it for user
Abhilash Sharma (MT19AIE202): Authentication, token generation
Puja Gupta (M21MA004): token verification
Durgesh Nath (MT19AIE235): Authentication
Saptashrungi Birajdar (B19CSE076): encryption
Apoorv Pal (B19CSE102): Roles and Permissions/Authorization
Shivam Kumar (B19CSE118): all are interacting with each other in MVC
Anshul Goyal (B19CSE012): it is not one way communication?
Ashish Jacob Sam (M21CS003): Because all components are interconnected
Sarthak Raj Jindal (B19CSE078): bidirectional
Sachin Tyagi (MT19AIE302): separation of concerns
Anshul Goyal (B19CSE012): layer woulld be slower
Amit Kumar Sharma (M20AIE213): Business logic code reusabality
Sasikanth Kotti (MT19AIE308): Maintenance of individual components
Vivek Saini (MT19AIE332): Faster computations
Ridhima Kohli (B19CSE071): easy debugging due to separation of Ui and controller
Ranjan Kumar (MT19AIE295): helps in achieve cohesion and reduce coupling
Suresh Bojjam (M20AIE313): simplifies the testing individual components
Ashish Jacob Sam (M21CS003): It separates Model from content. This way, multiple other service can access model without interfereing with each other
Shivam Kumar (B19CSE118): what is business logic code?
Abhilash Sharma (MT19AIE202): Code testability
Saptashrungi Birajdar (B19CSE076): How view changes model directly?
Patel Darsh Babubhai (B19CSE115): 3-tier also provide independence in form of layers as advantage, then how MVC is better?
Vivek Saini (MT19AIE332): Sir what are commercial applications of MVC ?
Shivam Kumar (B19CSE118): will we cover restful in detail later on in the course?
Apoorv Pal (B19CSE102): for components that do not require access to saved data in the database, view could interact with the controller directly
Shubham Singh (M21CS016): yes sir
Sasikanth Kotti (MT19AIE308): ETL appears to be following this pattern....
Shivam Kumar (B19CSE118): filter may also change the incoming data
Suresh Bojjam (M20AIE313): can you give one more example for pipe-and-filter
Suresh Bojjam (M20AIE313): Sir, mapReduce follows the pipe-and-filter pattern?
Suresh Bojjam (M20AIE313): yes sir. thanks.
Ranjan Kumar (MT19AIE295): yes
Shubham Singh (M21CS016): lexical analyzer, syntax analyzer and code generation kind of things will be performed in this pattern ??
Shubham Singh (M21CS016): ok sir
Apoorv Pal (B19CSE102): Is WebRTC a form of peer-to-peer?
Sushil Kumar Surana (MT19AIE324): 22 Jan will be too early.. may be a couple of more classes.. if possible??
Sachin Tyagi (MT19AIE302): yes, just have same timing for all class your and ram sir whatever it is so that we can plan
Sushil Kumar Surana (MT19AIE324): yes.. but we are not aware what exactly we will be studying.. so a few more classes will help us form it better..
Sushil Kumar Surana (MT19AIE324): 👍
Durgesh Nath (MT19AIE235): Thank you Sir
Abhilash Sharma (MT19AIE202): Thank you sir!
Sasikanth Kotti (MT19AIE308): Thankyou Sir...
Sushil Kumar Surana (MT19AIE324): thank you si
Abhijit S Iyer (M21CS001): Thank you sir